Gareth Davies

8 Venice Court, Wake Green Park, Moseley, Birmingham B13 9YL

me@garethdavies.me

07846861028

Summary

I am a passionate and highly skilled creative professional with nearly 10 years experience working with web sites and web applications. I am adaptable, self-motivated and organised in my working approach. I am currently working as Senior Developer at Just Checking, which demands a wealth of web experience; including technical, creative and client-facing skills. I have a wide skill-set that makes me an asset to have on any digital team, working on projects from initial briefs through to final implementation.

Employment

Senior Developer

Just Checking 2012 - present Since early 2012, I have been working for Just Checking as a Senior Developer. During my time at Just Checking, I have rebuilt their customer support dashboard and developed their new client application. These projects have seen me involved in writing project specifications, running user research sessions, as well as planning the user experience and making sure any work is on-brand. As a Senior Developer, part of my job is to support the junior developers at the company, helping them to learn and understand the development process and the techniques involved.

Front-End Web Developer

Birmingham City University 2010 - 2012

I began working for Birmingham City University in 2010 as part of the newly formed web team. My main responsibility in this role was to oversee the front-end development of websites within the university, primarily focusing on the main corporate site. During my time at the university, I converted the website to HTML5, introduced a mobile friendly responsive design and improved accessibility and usability through the strict application of web standards and iterative user testing.

Senior Web Designer

NTI Birmingham 2008 - 2010 In this role I was involved in numerous web projects which required me to provide cost and time estimations, deal with client requests and meetings, complete usability and accessibility testing, collaborate with other designers and developers and assign tasks to them whilst monitoring project development. During my time in this role I have developed my knowledge of ASP.NET, HTML5, CSS3 and JQuery.

Web Designer

Screen Media Lab 2003 - 2008 I joined Media Content Lab as a Web Designer in 2003. During this period I had a very diverse role working across a wide range of projects from graphic design, branding, and web design. I designed and built numerous websites using HTML, CSS, ASP and Flash technologies. Dealing with client meetings and enquiries gave me valuable experience in expressing creative ideas and processes.

Knowledge

Software & Languages
Tools & Databases

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, LESS, SASS, JSON, ASP.NET, PHP, Fireworks, Photoshop jQuery, Backbone.js, Marionette.js, Grunt, RequireJS, SQL Server, Wordpress

Education

1998 - 2001

BA(Hons) Design Studies University of Salford

1996 - 1998

A-Level - Design Studies, Physics & Geography

Cadbury College, Birmingham